ASSISTANT MANAGER OF OPERATIONS Summary

Resourceful Assistant Manager experienced in accomplishing management-level tasks. Track record of success includes training, store opening/closing and money handling. Highly responsible with strong accuracy and dedicated nature. Management experience, specialized in retail and customer service environments. Strong leader with excellent history of training new employees in effective sales strategies.

Skills

- Merchandising
- Good communication skills
- Organization
- Computer literate
- Team leadership experience
- Results-oriented mindset
- Clean and professional
- Inventory management
- Employee training
- Decision-making
- Managing retail build outs
- Customer outreach
- Leadership development
- Driving business growth

Experience

Immunotek | Stonecrest, GA Assistant Manager of Operations 10/2018 - Current

- Connected with customers daily to understand needs, provide assistance and collect feedback to optimize operations.
- Maintained high merchandising standards by building attractive displays and monitoring inventory levels.
- Maintained inventory accuracy by counting stock-on-hand and reconciling discrepancies.
- Organized and updated schedules to optimize coverage for expected customer demands.
- Operated cash register.
- Evaluated transactions for suspected fraud.
- Signed for incoming shipments in manager's absence.
- Described merchandise and services to customers.
- Answered questions and resolved concerns.
- Maintained store in clean and neat manner.
- Responded to safety and loss prevention incidents.
- Set up visually appealing promotional displays.
- Delegated tasks appropriate to individual employees to provide development opportunities.
- Managed inventory and stock levels in coordination with purchasing and receiving department.

Mfa Oil | Milan, MO Assistant Manager 08/2012 - 10/2018

- Planned and prepared workflow schedules, delegating tasks for 20-member team
- Cultivated hands-on training, assessment, guidance and performance monitoring programs to coach and mentor employees.
- Initiated inventory control measures to manage and replenish stock, maintain cost levels and meet customer demand.
- Delegated daily tasks to team members to optimize group productivity.
- Collaborated with store manager to develop strategies for achieving sales and profit goals.
- Mentored staff to enhance skills and achieve daily targets, using hands-on and motivational leadership.
- Completed inventory audits to identify losses and project demand.
- Directed and led employees, supervising activities to drive productivity and efficiency.
- Assisted General Manager in evaluating employee performance and cultivating improvement initiatives.
- Maintained inventory accuracy by counting stock-on-hand and reconciling discrepancies.
- Organized schedules, workflows and shift coverage to meet expected business demands.
- Managed personnel scheduling, facilitating adequate coverage to meet demand.
- Conducted job interviews, led employee performance evaluations with constructive feedback and rewarded top sales performers to attract and retain top-quality personnel.
- Trained all front of house staff on restaurant policies and procedures, guest service techniques and communication skills to ensure positive experience.
- Exhibited thorough knowledge of foods, beverages, supervisory duties, service techniques and guest interactions.
- Maximized team performance by training new employees on proper food handling, guest expectations and restaurant protocols.
- Assigned tasks and oversaw employees to ensure compliance with food safety procedures and quality control guidelines.
- Efficiently resolved problems or concerns to satisfaction of all involved parties.
- Scheduled and directed staff in daily work assignments to maximize productivity.
- Consistently maintained high levels of cleanliness, organization, storage, and sanitation of food and beverage products to ensure quality.
- Maintained cleanliness and sanitation across all food service, storage, and preparation stations.
- Trained workers in food preparation, money handling and cleaning roles to facilitate restaurant operations.

Fenix Parts Inc | Hurst, TX Sales Associate 01/2006 - 09/2009

- Stocked shelves and supplies and organized displays to focus customer attention on specific items.
- Demonstrated products to customers, discussed features and redirected objections to capture sales.
- Unboxed new merchandise and restocked shelves in appealing and organized arrangements to promote items.

- Helped customers sign up for loyalty programs and submitted completed paperwork.
- Used register system to ring up customer purchases, process payments and issue receipts.
- Performed floor moves, merchandising, display maintenance and housekeeping to keep sales areas well-stocked, organized and current.
- Educated customers on product and service offerings.
- Recommended merchandise to customers based on needs and preferences.
- Met or exceeded upselling, donation and credit card sign-up targets on consistent basis by leveraging excellent communication and interpersonal strengths.
- Readied merchandise for sales floor by marking items with identifying codes and accurate pricing.
- Recommended optimal merchandise based on customer needs and desires.
- Stayed up to date on store promotions, payment policies and security practices.
- Observed customer behaviors to identify security threats and escalate concerns to supervisors.
- Recognized by management for providing exceptional customer service.
- Improved operations by working with team members and customers to find workable solutions.
- Improved customer satisfaction by finding creative solutions to problems.
- Provided excellent service and attention to customers when face-to-face or through phone conversations.
- Worked closely with team members to deliver project requirements, develop solutions and meet deadlines.
- Mixed and matched paints according to customer specifications.

Education and Training

Bakersfield College | City , State Some College (No Degree) in Business Management Delano High School | City , State High School Diploma 06/1990